Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
The White Base left Northern Ireland
after repulsing Char's attack.
However, hiding inside the ship...
...was a young woman who had
snuck aboard under Char's orders.
Miharu Ratokie...
...wasn't a girl who had become
a spy by choice.
Amuro. I'm ready.
Roger that, Ms. Sayla!
Here I go!
We're gonna stall!
Please hurry!
It's okay!
Docking completed!
Roger. That's just 15 seconds!
It was just as Amuro had pointed out.
When the Gundam docked to become G-Bull,
the left side was totally unprotected.
Finding a solution to cover
this weakness in the armor...
...would be a top priority for improving
the Gundam's modular system.
The White Base crew are presently
above the Atlantic Ocean.
Their destination...
Across the Atlantic Ocean
The whale from the Federation Forces
was a lot larger than we thought.
Sir! We've received a message
from Captain Boone.
From Boone?
That Boone. He sent a spy
to infiltrate the Trojan Horse...
But how does he plan to retrieve the intel?
Sneak into an officer's room.
First, find out their intended destination.
Second, collect any data on the
capabilities of the Trojan Horse.
Have that information ready for me.
I'll contact you at 0500 hours.
Mr. Bright!
It's time to head up to the bridge!
Huh? Guess he's already gone up.
What was that?
I wonder what tore.
M-Mr. Kai.
Huh?
D-Don't scare me like that...
Who are you?
I'm sorry I scared you.
Huh?
Hey! It's you, Miharu!
Why are you here?
I wanted to be with you.
That's why I came aboard this ship.
Then... Where'd you get that uniform...?
And that gun?
Mr. Kai...
I already know.
You love your siblings.
It's not true that you came here for me.
It's not a lie!
It's... It's partly true...
Sh... You'd better come with me.
This is my room.
Who is she?
Don't ask such tactless questions.
Is... Is she your girlfriend?
Uh, yeah, something like that.
I'll drop her off in South America.
So keep it a secret, okay?
South America?
All right. I didn't see a thing.
Appreciate it... See ya!
The key code for the door is 3986.
Stay in here.
Where in South America are we going?
We're headed for a spaceship dock.
But that's about all the information
you're gonna get out of me.
If the White Base blew up before reaching
South America, neither of us would survive.
You have a point there.
I'll contact you on your wrist
radio at 0500 hours.
There's not much time.
What's he planning?
Civilian aircraft approaching
at 4 o'clock.
It's sending out a distress signal.
A distress signal?
Are you sure it's a civilian aircraft?
Can you confirm that, Fraw Bow?
Sir! I'm confirming it right now...
According to its registration number...
...it belongs to a fishery union
in the Verde Islands, sir.
All right!
Instruct them to enter from the rear deck.
Yes, sir.
Open Deck 4!
Prepare to dock a civilian plane.
I'll bet we're the first Zeons
to infiltrate the Trojan Horse.
Huh...
Don't say a word.
Huh?
Your Zeon accent is too strong.
Yes, sir...
Thanks!
Hurry with that!
It'll catch fire!
We were out checking for schools of fish.
A Zeon fighter plane
started shooting at us for fun.
When?
About 20 minutes ago.
It's been shot with unexploded
20mm shells.
We'll do makeshift repairs and provide you
with enough fuel to get you home.
Appreciate it.
However, you'll be restricted to that room.
I know, that's fine with me...
Hey! Carioca!
We'll send a repair invoice to the union.
Don't charge too much.
Hey. You think anyone at the union
will accept the invoice?
Good question.
Gotta go.
Where's the toilet?
Oh. Go straight, then turn right.
Thanks.
Turn right, there!
Don't go any further!
Gotcha.
Well, I suppose this is all new to him.
That's him!
No. 107. If you can speak aloud, answer me.
Where's the Trojan Horse heading?
A spaceship dock in South America.
Good. What else?
Nothing yet.
Good work.
Keep it up.
I feel much better!
What were you doing there?
Did you contact them?
Yeah.
How can you reach them from this distance?
It doesn't make sense.
I... I think so too.
But this is how my family and I
have been able to feed ourselves.
Well, I understand that.
Guess I'm getting you in trouble.
Me being a spy and all.
Well maybe...
They said a civilian aircraft came on board.
That's the only way they
could reach you by radio!
Listen! Whatever happens after this
has got nothing to do with you. Got that?
My sixth sense told me there's something
suspicious about that civilian aircraft!
Mr. Kai!
Stop! Someone make that aircraft stop!
They're spies!
Shoot 'em down!
What's the matter, Mr. Kai?
They're just fishermen...
Idiot!
Don't you think it's strange they approached
the White Base at a time like this?
Bright! You sure those guys weren't spies?
Did you check it thoroughly? Eh?!
Yes, we checked it all out.
We frisked the pilots as well.
We even confirmed that the airplane
genuinely belongs to a fishery union.
Y- Yeah, but still... It's possible that
Zeon soldiers stole the plane.
Kai. Do you happen to have any proof?
Um, no. It's just strange
that they'd come at this hour.
Looks like things went well.
So it's not the African front?
Yes. They're definitely headed for a
spaceship dock in South America, sir.
I'm glad they're not coming this way, but...
The Mad Angler has to stay here.
We're supposed to observe
the situation on the African front.
I used to be a pilot in my younger days.
May I borrow the mobile armor, sir?
The Grabro...? It's certainly ready, but...
I don't want to call it "revenge", but...
So far they've managed to sink
four of my mobile suits.
Please let me attack them.
If I use that mobile armor...
...even from this distance,
it'll catch up to the Trojan Horse.
Yes, you have my permission.
They still haven't gone.
They've appeared at 7 o'clock.
There's no way a submarine could
catch up to us. Just watch for missiles.
Incoming! Missiles detected!
Fire rear missiles!
7 o'clock!
A second and third wave of missiles!
Wait! Fourth and fifth wave
approaching from below!
Attack the submarine!
All units standby!
What do you think, Amuro?
Well, it's hard to decide what to deploy
when we barely know our opponent.
True.
We're over the ocean, so the Guncannon
and Guntank are at a disadvantage. So...
Mirai says mobile suits are heading this way.
I think so too. In that case, let's use
the Gundam and G-Fighter separately.
Objects approaching at 10 o'clock!
All hands, prepare for battle!
Three objects are approaching!
Portside! Put up a barrage!
Let's lift, all together now!
Here we go!
There are children on this ship?!
We'll take off in G-Armor mode.
We can bolt out in mid-air.
Roger.
I've got you now, Trojan Horse.
I'll avenge all of my men.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
The White Base...!
Amuro. Is the White Base badly damaged?
It'll be okay. It looks like they
only got part of the hatch.
I see.
What part of the ship was just hit?!
Deck 2!
Deck 2, give me a damage report!
That was a direct hit!
Wear this life jacket!
It's all for nothing if you don't survive!
And you?
I'm in the middle of fighting!
Let me help, please!
There's no way you can help!
Th-This is all my fault!
Hey...
You guys are in danger, Mr. Kai,
all because I gave them information...
The little information you gave them
wouldn't result in an attack like this.
I'm sorry! Kai! I'm the one who...!
This is all my fault, Kai!
Uh. Hey! Miharu!
- Amuro. Here we go. Gundam, bolt out!
- Roger!
4, 3, 2...
Where is it?!
Is that it?!
Take this!
So you finally showed up, Gundam.
Confident in your underwater combat skill?
Or are you underestimating ours?
Core Fighter power at 90, 95...
100! 120! Launching!
Oh! There it is!
All blocks, give me a damage report!
Can't we send out Kai's Core Fighter?!
The catapult's damaged.
We can't launch Core Fighters!
How about the Gunperry?
It's equipped with anti-submarine missiles!
Uh. You're right, sir.
I'll get Kai on it right away.
Fraw Bow! Get them to open Deck 3!
We'll be sending out the Gunperry!
Yes, sir!
Deck 3!
Prepare the Gunperry for launch!
Mr. Kai, where are you?
Please proceed to Deck 3!
Mr. Kai to Deck 3!
Miharu, hide someplace
where you can easily escape!
But everyone's fighting!
Let me help! Please! I can do it.
Why you...! You won't get away!
He's good.
Got one!
They've sunk Godard's Z'Gok!
You...!
Okay, now go!
Put out the fire!
The fire's out...
How's the White Base?!
Thruster output, decreased by 40 percent!
Yes, I know! Tell the crew to aim well
before firing the anti-submarine missiles!
Fraw Bow! How's the Gundam doing now?
There's no response yet.
I think he's struggling.
After all, the Gundam isn't equipped
with any weapons for underwater use.
Don't say that!
Sorry, sir.
What kind of weapons does this guy have
for underwater combat?
Here we go!
No good. If I don't lure him to the surface,
the Gundam doesn't have a chance!
You foolishly came underwater
to fight against my Grabro.
That was your mistake!
Wow, it's fast!
As I feared, the beam rifle's power...
...is halved when fired underwater.
How about that!
I've got you now, Gundam!
Oh no!
Are you okay?!
Y-Yeah, we're fine.
This is nothing!
Good! You kids are brave and strong!
Keep it up!
Kai! Please give me the chance to fight!
I can't let these kids die
when my sister and brother are safe!
Kikka! Come on!
There're still some fires to put out!
If I go back, I'll just continue
being used by Zeon.
Besides, I can't bear to just stand here,
watching from the sidelines!
But you're...
Mr. Kai! Please take off!
Okay! Where is Job right now?!
He's busy firing the machine guns!
Come with me!
I need a bombardier.
Huh?
You can launch missiles, can't you?!
Just tell me what to do!
So much for this mobile suit!
It's as helpless as a baby
before the power of my Grabro!
Why you...!
When you see the enemy blip
in the scope's cross-hairs, fire the missile!
Got it?!
Sure. I understand.
There!
I'm out of bullets and missiles!
Mr. Kai, please take over!
Roger!
You press one lever at a time!
Just stay calm.
Okay.
That one missed!
Next one!
Miharu! Fire! Fire!
Kai! I pressed the lever but it won't fire!
What?! Not now, at a time like this...!
It's no good...
That attack damaged the electrical circuit.
How can we defeat the enemy?
If only we could move the lever
on the side of the catapult...
Miharu! Where are you going?!
Kai! You said there's a lever
on the side of the catapult, right?
Miharu! It's too dangerous!
Is... Is this it?
Miharu! Listen, you gotta do it properly!
You know how to do it?!
Kai! Steer the plane toward the enemy!
Kai! The enemy's coming straight at us!
Yeah! Miharu! We did it!
Let's finish you off!
The other Z'Gok was destroyed as well?!
Your mistake was tearing off
the Gundam's leg.
It's allowed me to move more easily!
Hey, Miharu! What's keeping you?
Come back up here, Miharu!
Mr. Kai! Watch out!
You gotta land on the ship now!
Roger that!
And this Miharu disappeared?
Yes. Apparently, she and Kai launched
together on the Gunperry.
Just who is she?
Do you know her?
No, sir. Nobody knows her.
Right?
Yes.
She was a stowaway.
A stowaway?!
So you knew her.
No, sir.
I saw a young lady go into Mr. Kai's room...
But then the enemy showed up, so...
Miharu... She's gone...
I'm so glad I met you.
Oh, Gil and Milly?
There's no need to worry about them...
They'll live a much better life than we did.
After all, the world won't be this awful
forever, will it?
Right, Kai?
Why did you have to die?!
Federation Forces Headquarters at Jaburo.
Char commands an assault on the base...
´
...while Amuro runs into Matilda's fiance.
War mercilessly destroys a life...
...as well as anger, and sorrow.
Mobile Suit Gundam.
Tragedy in Jaburo.
Will you be able to survive?
Next Time
Tragedy in Jaburo
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...